# Rishabh Iyer

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

My current research is centered around developing systems and techniques that enable developers to reason precisely about the performance behavior of their code *before* it is deployed. My dissertation work introduced the notion of latency interfaces: simple, succinct programs that summarize a system's latency behaviour just like semantic interfaces such as code documentation and specifications summarize functionality.

## EDUCATION

## Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne (EPFL)

2017-2023

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD), Computer Science Thesis: Latency Interfaces for Systems Code

Advisors: Prof. George Candea & Prof. Katerina Argyraki

## Indian Institute of Technology Bombay (IITB)

2013-2017

Bachelor of Technology with Honours, Electrical Engineering

Thesis: Performance Modelling and Dynamic Scheduling for Heteregeneous ISA Processors

Advisor: Prof. Virendra Singh

## Professional Experience

#### Postdoctoral Scholar at EPFL

Sep 2023 - Present

Supervisor: Prof. George Candea

Worked on a wide range of topics centred around on building systems with predictable performance behavior

#### Visiting Researcher at UC Berkeley

Sep 2022 - Feb 2023

Supervisor: Prof. Sylvia Ratnasamy

Worked on Performance Interfaces for Hardware Accelerators

## Summer Intern at EPFL

May - July 2016

Supervisor: Prof. Babak Falsafi

Ported the QFlex Trace Simulator from QEMU 2.3 to QEMU 2.6

#### AWARDS

• ACM SIGOPS Dennis M. Ritchie Doctoral Dissertation Award

2023

• Best Paper Award

VDAT 2019

• EPFL Doctoral Fellowship

#### 2017

#### Publications

# • Achieving Microsecond-Scale Tail Latency Efficiently with Approximate Optimal Scheduling Rishabh Iyer, Musa Unal, Marios Kogias, George Candea.

Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP), 2023. Acceptance rate: 18.7%

## • The Case for Performance Interfaces for Hardware Accelerators

Rishabh Iyer, Jiacheng Ma, Katerina Argyraki, George Candea, Sylvia Ratnasamy. Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS), 2023. Acceptance rate: 26.4%

## • Performance Interfaces for Network Functions

Rishabh Iyer, Katerina Argyraki, George Candea.

Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2022. Acceptance rate: 19.7%

## • Bypassing the Load Balancer Without Regrets.

Marios Kogias, Rishabh Iyer, Edouard Bugnion.

Symposium on Cloud Computing (SoCC), 2020. Acceptance rate: 24.4%

## • Classification-Based Scheduling in Heterogeneous-ISA Architectures

Nirmal Boran, Dinesh Yadav, Rishabh Iyer.

Symposium on VLSI Design and Test (VDAT), 2020. Acceptance rate: 28.7%

## • Verifying Software Network Functions with No Verification Expertise

Arseniy Zaostrovnykh, Solal Pirelli, Rishabh Iyer, Luis Pedrosa, Matteo Rizzo, Katerina Argyraki, George

Candea.

Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (SOSP), 2019. Acceptance rate: 13.7%

Performance Modelling and Dynamic Scheduling on Heterogeneous-ISA Architectures
 Nirmal Boran, Dinesh Yadav, Rishabh Iyer
 Symposium on VLSI Design and Test (VDAT), 2019. Acceptance rate: 27.3%
 Awarded Best Paper

## • Performance Contracts for Software Network Functions

Rishabh Iyer, Luis Pedrosa, Arseniy Zaostrovnykh, Solal Pirelli, Katerina Argyraki, George Candea. Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2019. Acceptance rate: 14.7%

• Automated Synthesis of Adversarial Workloads for Network Functions Luis Pedrosa, Rishabh Iyer, Arseniy Zaostrovnykh, Jonas Fietz, Katerina Argyraki. ACM SIGCOMM Conference (SIGCOMM), 2018. Acceptance rate: 18%

TEACHING

A SSISTA NITSHIDS

CS 522: Principles of Computer Systems (EPFL)

Fall 2019, 2020, 2021, 2022

Assistantships CS 305: Software Engineering (EPFL)

Fall 2018

MA 207: Analysis 4 - Vector Calculus (EPFL)

Spring 2018, 2019

PH 107: Quantum Physics (IITB)

Fall 2014

## RESEARCH MENTORSHIP

• Musa Unal (PhD student at EPFL) Cooperative scheduling for microsecond-scale data center applications Second author on publication at SOSP'23. Summer 2022 - Present

Second author on publication at SOSP'23.
Jiacheng Ma (PhD student at EPFL)

Fall 2022 - Present

Performance Interfaces for Hardware Accelerators Second author on publication at HotOS'23, lead author on submission to OSDI'24.

• Ayoub Chouak (summer intern at EPFL)

Leveraging performance interfaces to identify constant-time violations in cryptographic code

Significant contributor to publication at NSDI'22.

• Yugesh Kothari (PhD student at EPFL)
Performance interfaces for eBPF offloads in the Linux kernel
Significant contributor to the PIX open source tool.

Fall 2022

• Kartikeya Kumar Dwivedi (PhD student at EPFL) Enabling Safe, Concurrent, and Flexible Fast-path Application Logic in the OS

Summer 2023 - Present

Narek Galstyan (PhD student at UC Berkeley)
 Application-integrated record and replay for distributed systems

Fall 2022 - Present

Rathin Singla (PhD student at UCLA)
 A verified, extensible transport stack

Fall 2022 - Present